{"name": "65E  2007-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. In the diagram below, B is the midpoint of AC and C is the midpoint of AD. The length of BC is 14 cm. What is the length, in centimeters, of AD \uff1f", "choices": {"A": " 28", "B": " 35", "C": " 42", "D": " 49", "E": " 56"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2.  If \uff0b 8 = 4, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": " 8", "B": " ", "C": " 0", "D": " ", "E": " -4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3.  Vehicle A averages 17 miles per gallon of gasoline, and Vehicle B averages 45 miles per gallon of gasoline. At these rates, how many more gallons of gasoline does Vehicle A need than Vehicle B to make a 1,53 0-mile trip?", "choices": {"A": " 31", "B": " 34", "C": " 56", "D": " 62", "E": " 90"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4.  A square has an area of 64 square inches. How many inches long is each side of the square?", "choices": {"A": " 8", "B": " 16", "C": " 32", "D": " 128", "E": " 256"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5.  Which of the following are the coordinates of the unlabeled vertex of the parallelogram shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below?", "choices": {"A": " (2,7)", "B": " (2,8)", "C": " (,4)", "D": " (3,7)", "E": " (5,3)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6.  Natiya's  mother's  age in whole\tyears is 4 times Natiya's age in whole years. The sum of these 2 ages is 35 years. What is Natiya's mother's age in whole years?", "choices": {"A": " 26", "B": " 28", "C": " 30", "D": " 31", "E": " 35"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7.  If \u2220ABC is a right angle and D is in the interior of \u2220ABC, which of the following CANNOT be  the measure of \u2220DBC?", "choices": {"A": " 20\u00b0", "B": " 40\u00b0", "C": " 60\u00b0", "D": " 80\u00b0", "E": " 100\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8.  Jack has a  blue sweatshirt,  a  black sweatshirt,  and a tan sweatshirt.  He also has a pair of  blue pants , a pair of black pants, and a pair of tan pants. How many different sweatshirt-pants combinations does Jack have with exactly 1 sweatshirt and 1 pair of pants in each combination?", "choices": {"A": " 1", "B": " 3", "C": " 6", "D": " 9", "E": " 27"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9.  50% of 8 is equal to 25% of what number?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " 4", "C": " 6", "D": " 16", "E": " 64"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10.  All 30 students in a history class took 2 tests. Of these students, 28 passed the first test and 25 passed  the second test. What is the maximum possible number of students who passed both tests?", "choices": {"A": " 23", "B": " 25", "C": " 27", "D": " 28", "E": " 30"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11.  What is the largest value of x  for  which  there  exists  a real value of y such that x2 + y2 = 324 ?", "choices": {"A": " 18", "B": " 162", "C": " 306", "D": " 324", "E": " 648"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  An advertisement shows a stereo system at  off the regular  price of  $675. An  8% sales  tax  will  be applied to the sale price of the system. A customer buying the stereo  system  gives  the  sales  clerk $500.  How  much change, if any, should the customer receive?", "choices": {"A": " $14", "B": " $42", "C": " $50", "D": " $86", "E": " None; the customer still owes $229."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13.  Which of the following numbers is NOT a real number?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14.  Which of the following is a factored form of the expression 36x2 -49y12 \uff1f", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " (36 - 49)(x - y6)(x + y6)", "C": " (6x - 7y6)(6x + 7y6)", "D": " (36x - y6)(x + 49y6)", "E": " (6x2 - 7y12)(6x2 + 7y12)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Each square in the grid below measures 1 unit on a side. Each vertex of the shaded  polygon is an intersection of 2 grid lines. What is the area, in square units, of the shade polygon?", "choices": {"A": " 4.0", "B": " 4.5", "C": " 5.0", "D": " 5.5", "E": " 6.0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16.  The height, h, of  a  projectile, in feet above the ground, is given by the function h(t) = -4t2 + 40t where t represents time, in seconds. How many feet above the ground is the projectile when t = 5 ?", "choices": {"A": " 300", "B": " 280", "C": " 171", "D": " 160", "E": " 100"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  A   5-pound   bag  of   onions  costs $1.95  at   Grocery Garden.  A 2-pound  bag of  the same type of onions costs $0.88 at Food Fair. How much cheaper,  per pound, are the Grocery Garden onions than the Food Fair onions?", "choices": {"A": " $0.05", "B": " $0.15", "C": " $0.21", "D": " $0.54", "E": " $1.07"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18.  (x3 + 8)(x3 - 8) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": " 2x3", "B": " x6", "C": " x6 - 64", "D": " x9 - 64", "E": " x6 - 16x3 - 64"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19.  Delon set his car's trip odometer to 0.0 miles before he traveled to visit a friend. He traveled  at  an  average speed of 65 mph for 2.5 hours and then took  a 30-minute break. Then he traveled at an average speed of 55 mph  until  his trip odometer  read 245.0 miles. How many hours did Del on travel after his break?", "choices": {"A": " 1.0", "B": " 1.5", "C": " 2.0", "D": " 2.5", "E": " 3.0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20.  In   the\tstandard (x,y) coordinate plane: A has coordinates (0,3) and B has coordinates (-6,9). What are the coordinates of the midpoint of AB \uff1f", "choices": {"A": " (-6,6)", "B": " (-6,12)", "C": " (-3,3)", "D": " (-3,6)", "E": " (3,-3)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21.  Andre has a rectangular garden in his backyard. He is preparing to put fencing along the edge of the garden, which is 12 feet by 10 feet.  One long  side  of  the garden is along his house, so he will only need to fence 3 sides. How many feet of fencing will Andre need?", "choices": {"A": " 22", "B": " 32", "C": " 34", "D": " 44", "E": " 120"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22.  What is the slope of the line represented by the equation 4y -  8x = 5 ?", "choices": {"A": " -8", "B": " ", "C": " 2", "D": " 4", "E": " 8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23.  At 6:00 A.M . the temperature was 30.6 \u00b0C at the Sleepy Bear Campground.  At  12:00 noon  t\u0148e  temperature  was 31.8\u00b0C. If the temperature rose  at  a constant  rate,  at what time that morning was it 31.0\u00b0C ?", "choices": {"A": " 7:00 A.M.", "B": " 8:00 A.M.", "C": " 9:00 A.M.", "D": " 10:00 A.M.", "E": " 11:00 A.M."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The expression given below is equivalent to which of the following expressions?(x3 + 2x2 - 6) - 2(x4 - 3x3 + 2x2 + x - 1)", "choices": {"A": " x15 - 7", "B": " -2x4 + 7x3 - 2x2 - 2x - 4", "C": " -2x4 - 2x3 + 4x2 - x - 7", "D": " -2x4 - 5x3 + 6x2 + 2x - 1", "E": " -6x15"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25.  To rescue a cat, the top of an 8-foot ladder is placed against  a tree limb at the  place where the cat is sitting, as shown in the figure below. The horizontal distance from the base of the ladder to the point directly below the  cat  is  about 3 feet.  What is  the approximate  height of   the tree limb, in feet, at the place where the cat is sitting?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 5", "C": " 7", "D": " 9", "E": " 11"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26.  A data set has 5 data  points. For this data  set,  the mean, the median, and  the mode are each equal to 10. Four of the 5 points are 8, 10, 10, and 15. Which of the following is the 5th data point?", "choices": {"A": " 7", "B": " 8", "C": " 9", "D": " 10", "E": " 17"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27.  In  a  certain   number  sequence,  each  element  after the 1st element is the result of multiplying the previous element   by  3  and  adding   2  to  that  product.  The 3rd element   in   the  sequence   is  53.  What   is  the 1st element?", "choices": {"A": " 1", "B": " 5", "C": " 7", "D": " 17", "E": " 47"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28.  If \u4e28x + 8 \u4e28= 32, what are the possible values for x?", "choices": {"A": " -40 and 24", "B": " -24 and 24", "C": " -24 and 40", "D": " -8 and 8", "E": " 24 and 40"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29.  For all real numbers w, x, y, and z, such that x + y + z\uff1d 73 and w &lt; y, which of the following statements is true?", "choices": {"A": " x + y + w \uff1e 73", "B": " x + y + w = 73", "C": " w + y + z = 73", "D": " x + y + w \uff1c 73", "E": " x + w + z \uff1c 73"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. In the figure below, line q is parallel to line r, C is the center of the circle, AE and BD both go through C, q  is  tangent to the circle at B, F lies on , and the measure  of \u2220FAC is  145\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220BCE ?", "choices": {"A": " 145\u00b0", "B": " 90\u00b0", "C": " 65\u00b0", "D": " 55\u00b0", "E": " 35\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31.  If the sum of 2 positive prime numbers is prime, then one of these prime numbers must be:", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " 3", "C": " 5", "D": " 7", "E": " 11"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. The figure below represents a certain race along a straight  course. The race started  at S and finished at F. A certain runner participating in this race clocked elapsed times tA, tB, tC, tD, and tF minutes from S to points A, B, C, D, and F, respectively. If BC, for example, denotes the distance between points B and C, and all distances are measured in kilometers, which of the following expressions necessarily represents the runner's average speed for this race, in kilometers per minute?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33.  The    triangle  shown  below  has  a  hypotenuse  with  a length of 10 meters. The measure of \u2220A is 25\u00b0 and the measure of \u2220B is 65\u00b0. Which of the following is closest to the length, in meters, of AC ?(Note:  sin 25\u00b0 \u2248 0.4226    cos 25\u00b0 \u2248 0.9063     tan 25\u00b0 \u2248 0.4663)", "choices": {"A": " 4.2", "B": " 4.7", "C": " 6.0", "D": " 8.0", "E": " 9.1"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. What is the value of . when x = 3 and y = -2 ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35.  As shown in the figure below, with angles as marked, a pole casts a shadow that is 14 feet long. Which of the following is closest to the height of the pole, in feet?", "choices": {"A": " 20", "B": " 24", "C": " 28", "D": " 30", "E": " 46"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36.  In the diagram below, \u25b3ABC is isosceles. The measure of \u2220ABC is 3 times the measure of \u2220CAB. What is the measure of \u2220DCB ?", "choices": {"A": " 36\u00b0", "B": " 54\u00b0", "C": " 90\u00b0", "D": " 108\u00b0", "E": " 126\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Use the following information to answer questions 37-39.The coordinates of the vertices of \u25b3ABO are shown in the standard  (x,y)  coordinate  plane  below. Square  CDEO  is shown shaded. Point C lies on BO, point D lies on AB, and point E lies on AO.37. What is the slope of ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " 0", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Use the following information to answer questions 37-39.The coordinates of the vertices of \u25b3ABO are shown in the standard  (x,y)  coordinate  plane  below. Square  CDEO  is shown shaded. Point C lies on BO, point D lies on AB, and point E lies on AO.38. Which of the following is closest to the perimeter, in coordinate units , of \u25b3ABO ?", "choices": {"A": " 8.0", "B": " 10.8", "C": " 12.0", "D": " 13.8", "E": " 42.0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Use the following information to answer questions 37-39.The coordinates of the vertices of \u25b3ABO are shown in the standard  (x,y)  coordinate  plane  below. Square  CDEO  is shown shaded. Point C lies on BO, point D lies on AB, and point E lies on AO.39. What is the value of tan(\u2220EAD)?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40.  A quality control inspector at a factory took a sample of  b items from a production  line and found that a  of the items were defective. Which of the following is a general expression  for the fraction of the sample that was NOT defective?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41.  Which of the following number line graphs shows the solution set of 3(x + 2) + 1 \u2264 4x + 15?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42.  A rectangular prism with its dimensions in centimeters is shown in the figure below. What is the prism's total surface area, in square centimeters?", "choices": {"A": " 184", "B": " 160", "C": " 144", "D": " 105", "E": " 92"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43.  In  the  figure  below, AE is  parallel  to BC\uff0cthe  measure of \u2220D is 72\u00b0, and the measure of \u2220E is 40\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220BCD ?", "choices": {"A": " 108\u00b0", "B": " 110\u00b0", "C": " 112\u00b0", "D": " 130\u00b0", "E": " 140\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44.  What is the area of the trapezoid below, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": " 36", "B": " 45", "C": " 48", "D": " 60", "E": " 72"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45.  What is the solution set of  ?", "choices": {"A": " {2}", "B": " {8}", "C": " {-8, 2}", "D": " {-2, 8}", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. A pond's length, represented by AB, is determined by using right triangle \u25b3ABC, shown in the figure below. The  distance from A to C is 40 meters and the measure of \u2220CBA is 28\u00b0. Which of the following expressions represents the length, in meters, of the pond?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " 40 sin 28\u00b0", "E": " 40 tan 28\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47.  The 5 positive  integers x, x, x, y, and z have an  average of x. Which of the following equations must be true?", "choices": {"A": " y = -z", "B": " y = z", "C": " y + z = 0", "D": " y + z = x", "E": " y + z = 2x"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48.  Which of the following pairs of functions, f(x) and g(x)\uff0cform  the  composite  function ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.For exercise, Jill and Matt run on a 400-meter-long oval track. Jill and  Matt each run  10 laps daily and both run in the same lane.49. One day, Jill and Matt began at the same point, but ran around the track in opposite directions. Jill ran at a constant speed that was 2 meters per second faster than Matt's constant speed. Jill passed  Matt  for  the  first time in 40 seconds. Jill ran at a constant rate of how many meters per second?", "choices": {"A": " 4", "B": " 5", "C": " 6", "D": " 8", "E": " 10"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.For exercise, Jill and Matt run on a 400-meter-long oval track. Jill and  Matt each run  10 laps daily and both run in the same lane50. Today, Jill averaged  70 seconds per lap until she began the last lap. She then slowed down. She averaged 72 seconds per lap for her daily run. How many seconds did Jill take to run the last lap?", "choices": {"A": " 52", "B": " 63", "C": " 72", "D": " 74", "E": " 90"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.For exercise, Jill and Matt run on a 400-meter-long oval track. Jill and  Matt each run  10 laps daily and both run in the same lane.51. Matt ran 4 laps in 5 minutes. At what average rate, in meters per second, did Matt run these 4 laps?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " 5", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52.  A circle in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane  is tangent  to  the x-axis  and  has its center at (2,-2). Where is the point (0,-2) located?", "choices": {"A": " Inside the circle", "B": " Outside the circle", "C": " On the x-axis", "D": " On the circle", "E": " Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53.  A window is a rectangle with a semicircle whose diameter is a side of the rectangle. The window  is shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below, where 1 coordinate unit represents 1 foot. The coordinates  of 5 points on  the border of  the window are given. What is the area, in square feet, of the window?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 6 + \u03c0", "C": " 6 + 2\u03c0", "D": " 8 + \u03c0", "E": " 8 + 2\u03c0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54.  A  function f(x) is one-to-one  if and only if each x in the domain of f(x) corresponds to a unique f(x) and each f(x) corresponds to a unique x. One of the following is the graph of a one-to-one function f(x). Which graph is it?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55.  What is the distance, in coordinate units, between the points (p, p + 1) and (2p, p - I) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " p2 + 4", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. In the figure below, \u25b3ABC is a right triangle with all 3  sides   of different   lengths. What    is   the    value  of sin2A + sin2B?", "choices": {"A": " 1", "B": " 2", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57.  In isosceles trapezoid ABCD below, E is   the  intersect   ion of the diagonals. The length of AB is 6 inches, the lengths of AE and BE are  4 inches, the length  of CE is 10 inches, and the measures of \u2220CDE and \u2220DCE are equal. What is the length , in inches, of CD \uff1f", "choices": {"A": " 10", "B": " 14", "C": " 15", "D": " 16", "E": " 20"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58.  Which of the following matrices, when substituted for T, satisfies the matrix equation below?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59.  If , then (n - 1)! = ?", "choices": {"A": " 15", "B": " 24", "C": " 60", "D": " 120", "E": " 720"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60.  What is the ratio of the diameter to the circumference of a circle?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " \u03c0", "E": " 2\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}]}